NIKUNJ JADHAV

nixkj3@gmail.com | +91 7977064992 | linktree/Nixk07 | linkedin/nikunj-jadhav

Profile

DevOps engineer with **3+ years** of experience in designing enterprise IT infrastructure and implementing CI/CD pipelines.Proficient in coding, scripting, and automating workflows, with strong debugging skills across **cloud-based environments**.

Skills Certification

Programming Languages: C++, Python, Bash

Databases: MySQL, SQL Services (SSIS, SSRS), phpMyAdmin

Version Control: Git, Github, BitBucket

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JS, PHP, Yii2, Flask

Python Libraries: Flask

Cloud Providers: AWS, Azure, GCP

Container orchestration: Docker, K8s, Helm

Project management tool: JIRA

Design & Documentation: Canva, Notion

Azure Fundamental Credly Porfolio AWS Badges:

Storage, Compute, Serverless

PubSub+ Cloud: Solace Certified

Developer practitioner, EDA-practitioner,

Solutions consultant

Work Experience

DevOps Engineer April 2024 - Current

Solace, Mumbai

- Working as a Junior DevOps Engineer, monitoring daily alerts for Segmentors and Queues using DataDog Monitoring Agent.
- Setting up a cron script for the automation of Daily alerts & monitoring the Uptime of the servers.
- Technologies: Solace, Bash, C, JS, DataDog, etc.

Cloud Associate

April 2022 - September 2023

SaphhireInfoTech Ventures, Mumbai

- Worked as a Cloud Associate, creating daily reports in Excel & handling client mail & processing requests.
- Setting up application servers based on various requirements on the cloud while doing on-prem. to cloud migration.
- I also helped create **disaster recovery plans** for various clients, ensuring efficient system operational recovery to their DR site during a catastrophic app failure.
- Technologies: Azure, VM, Storage, S2S, and more; AWS services include EC2, S3, Cloudwatch, VPC, Lambda, IAM, etc.

Software Intern

February 2022 - April 2022

Synergy Technology, Mumbai

- Built a CRUD app with Admin Login, phpMyAdmin Database & Flask used with Foreign Key Tables for Music Webpage.
- I built the **plugin** from scratch, adding ease of use for the users. It's integrated into **WordPress**.
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, WordPress, PHPMyAdmin, PHP 7, Yii2, Flask.

Web-Development Intern

February 2019 - March 2019

Sahu Technologies, Mumbai

- Designed Dynamic UI pages for Hotel Management Systems and Library Management Systems."
- Created a multi-page interactive website, linked it to a database, and deployed it using "PHPMyAdmin."
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHPMyAdmin.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (BSc-IT), Mumbai University

CGPA: 7.83/10 2019 - 2021

Diploma in Computer Science, Maharashtra State Board of Technical Education (MSBTE)

73% 2016 - 2019

Projects

Yoga Plus - IIT Bombay's EdTech Hackathon

- Developed an **Android** app & web app in **Flutter** that assists users in performing yoga and workouts by using machine learning models in **TensorFlow Lite**. The user's stats were stored in **Firebase**.
- The web app uses the webcam to capture images and infers poses using the MAX deep learning model
- Technologies: HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, Tensorflow.js, PoseNet, Model Asset Exchange.

Achievements

Volunteering

Youth Volunteer at HariPrabodham [2017- Present]

Stood 7th in the IIT Bombay EdTech Hackathon Stood 3rd in the Apscript Hackathon Selected in the CII - Debate Competition, State-Level